Guide to the Television Scripts Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Television scripts collection
1957-1960
YCAL MSS 383
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
1.4
(4 boxes)
The collection consists of typescript copies of scripts for television programs produced by the Columbia Broadcasting System and United States Steel Hour from 1957 to 1960. Included are scripts written by Rod Serling, Tad Mosel, Leonard Spigelgass, Aaron Spelling, and George Bellak, among others. The scripts seem to have been compiled for a class on television writing which was taught by David Davidson in the Yale School of Drama beginning in the mid-1960s.
Davidson, David, 1908-1985
Bellak, George, 1919-2002
Blacker, Irwin R.
Brandel, Marc, 1919-1994
Browne, Howard, 1907-1999
Coneybeare, Rod
De Felitta, Frank, 1921-2016
Hailey, Arthur
McGreevey, John
Monash, Paul, 1917-2003
Mosel, Tad
Reisman, Philip, Jr.
Serling, Rod, 1924-1975
Spelling, Aaron
Spies, Adrian
Spigelgass, Leonard, 1908-1985
Sproat, Ronald
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the Yale Drama Library, 2007.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of typescript copies of scripts for television programs produced by the Columbia Broadcasting System and United States Steel Hour from 1957 to 1960. Included are scripts written by Rod Serling, Leonard Spigelgass, Tad Mosel, Aaron Spelling, and George Bellak, among others. The scripts seem to have been compiled for a class on television writing which was taught by David Davidson in the Yale School of Drama beginning in the mid-1960s.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Columbia Broadcasting System Productions, 1957-1960. II. United States Steel Hour Productions, 1959.
United States Steel hour (Television program); Television authorship; Television plays; Television programs -- United States; Television writers; Television scripts; Davidson, David, 1908-1985; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc; Yale School of Drama
- Columbia Broadcasting System Productions, 1957-1960; Series I; 1.2; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Bellak, George. "The Troublemakers" (November 21, 1957) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Brandel, Marc. "Eight Feet to Midnight", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Browne, Howard. "Seven Against the Wall" (November 12, 1958) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coneybeare, Arthur Rodney. "In Love with a Stranger" (July 18, 1957) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - DeFelitta, Frank and Blacker, Irwin. "Satan in Salem" (January 27, 1957) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Hailey, Arthur. "Diary of a Nurse" (May 7, 1959) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Marks, Laurence. "Death and Taxes" (June 26, 1957) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - McGreevey, John. "The Long Count" (February 21, 1957) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mosel, Tad. "The Innocent Sleep" (June 5, 1958) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mosel, Tad. "The Morning Face" (October 7, 1957) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reisman Jr., Philip. "First Prize For Murder" (September 16, 1957) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ross, Jerome. "Act of Mercy" (October 14, 1957) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Schneider, Will and Goldberg, Herman. "The Years in Between" (April 1, 1957) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Serling, Rod
    - "The Dark Side of the Earth" (September 19, 1957) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "One For the Angels" (May 18, 1959) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "The Rank and File" (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "A Town Has Turned to Dust" (June 19, 1958) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Escape Clause", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "The Lonely", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Mr. Denton on Doomsday", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Simon, Mayo. "The Deaf Heart", 1957 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Spelling, Aaron. "The Last Man" (January 9, 1958) (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Spies, Adrian. "Mad Bomber" (April 18, 1957) (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Spigelgass, Leonard and Monash, Paul. "Helen Morgan" (May 16, 1957) (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Wagner, Walter. "Diary of a Roman GI" (March 17, 1957) (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Garry Moore Show (March 29, 1960) (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Garry Moore Show (May 3, 1960) (Box 3, Folder 27)
- United States Steel Hour Productions, 1959; Series II; 0.2; (1 box)
  - Sproat, Ronald F. "Rachel's Summer" (October 7, 1959) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Van Scoyk, Bob. "The Yum-Yum Girl", undated (Box 4, Folder 29)